Do you know why North and South Korea
are enemies? They have no diplomatic
relations, divided by walls and barbed
wire, and have technically been at war
for decades, even though just 100 years
ago they were one country known as the
Korean Empire. But in 1910, Japan,
seeking to expand its empire, annexed
the Korean Peninsula, and Korea remained
under Japanese control until the end of
World War II. Just days before Japan's
surrender, Soviet troops entered the
peninsula from the north while the US
advanced from the south. To prevent the
USSR from taking full control of the
region, the United States proposed
dividing Korea along the 38th parallel,
a temporary solution for joint
administration until an independent
Korean government could be formed. But
as tensions between the two superpowers
grew during the Cold War, the country
was never reunited and Korea fell under
the influence of two opposing
ideologies, communism and capitalism. As
a result, two countries were formed,
each believing that the entire peninsula
should be united under its rule. This
led North Korea to launch a war, nearly
capturing the entire South. South Korea
asked for help, and the US, leading UN
forces, pushed the North Korean army
back almost to the Chinese border. China
unofficially entered the conflict on the
north side, sending about 2 million
volunteers, while the USSR provided
military equipment and weapons.
Eventually, the front line moved back to
almost the 38th parallel, and it was
decided to sign an armistice. But a
peace treaty was never concluded. So,
the two countries are still in a state
of war.